[Music]
okay hello and welcome to boosto
productivity with business Central I'm
Ivan ktic I'm a product manager in
business Central and I will take you
through uh this uh session uh the agenda
today is uh sort of split in two parts
first we'll talk very briefly about some
of the user experience improvements we
have in U our mobile client there's also
a dedicated session for that later on
I'll reference it in the in the deck and
after that we'll talk about uh some of
the improvements uh that were brought in
2024 release Wave 1 in the web client so
let's start uh with uh quick
improvements that we've added uh to a
mobile client as you can see on the
screen uh uh on on the right part of the
screen we've uh allowed we've added
access to worksheets from our uh mobile
client so you can now access worksheet
Pages uh you can see the header details
you can see the line details and you can
actually also see the the fact boxes and
the footer details of uh uh of the
worksheet uh pages so there's no more uh
there's no limitation uh any more of uh
looking at the worksheet pages from
version uh
24 uh another thing that we are making
uh uh with 2024 release wave 1 is we are
making modern action bar uh that we
introduced three releases ago uh
mandatory uh apart from making it
mandatory U you will see there are some
uh minor improvements that have been
also added uh to the overall
action bar to sort of lower the the
impact and lower the impact of the
change of uh making the action modern
action bar uh experience mandatory uh
all of our users when they upgrade uh to
uh version 24 we'll get a call out uh
that will explain and point to a video
that uh runs through the changes that
are being introduced with uh modern
action bar apart from all the good all
the goodness that the modern action bar
brought like three releases ago like a
very flexible
personalization uh optimized layout of
the action groups on the pages and
introduction of the split button the
2024 release Wave 1 version of the
action bar also has as you can see this
a couple of these new icons so we've
added the co-pilot icon we've also
spared some of the captions to a
accommodate for space in the action bar
and if you belong to one to the category
of people who still want to keep the the
the the the things the way that they are
each and every user in the my settings
uh page will have an option to opt out
of uh the modern action bar experience
the other thing that is worth to note is
that the admins also have a way of uh
enabling or disabling that for uh all
the user
users another new thing that uh was
added in 2024 release Wave 1 is a new
date picker control we got a lot of
feedback that uh with old date picker
control sometimes it was very difficult
to especially if you if you needed to
explore and find the dates that were far
in the past or far in the future and we
know there are scenarios when when these
things uh uh when these things are are
needed so hence we've introduced a uh
new dat picker control it U it sort of
has a similar set of uh shortcuts that
the old one had it is aligned with uh
the DAT picker controls used in other
Microsoft products which means if you
know how to use the date picker control
uh I don't know in uh Word Excel or or
somewhere you'll be able to uh to use it
uh in
here
um 2024 release Wave 1 uh also
introduces um adds action to sort of a
platform generated uh to platform
generated
errors uh once these errors occur and
there is U no partner and Microsoft as
well we have a ton of uh old Legacy code
and uh a couple of releases back we
start introducing actions to uh error
dialogues and to inline validation
dialogues and the problem with the
Legacy code is that there is so many uh
places where uh various validation
errors are shown and so on so we thought
how do we make how do we make that
Legacy code base uh also actionable uh
for the for the end users because we saw
that these things are very useful in uh
unblocking the users so we this release
you actually do get actions for all of
those Legacy platform generated errors
by default with no uptake in your
extensions or with no additional effort
on the developer side uh to to to get
those actions you will see them uh
actually how how they look like uh in
the
demo and other thing that we've noticed
is that uh there's a category of of
Errors where um business Central can
help either by navigating the user to a
page where they can actually fix the
error or by providing an an action that
can fix the error but there are cases
where the user simply doesn't have
permissions
or or needs help uh from another user uh
to get unblocked and with this release
we are providing an easy way to uh share
details about the error messages be
through teams or uh via email so let's
say that you want to ask for for help
from your colleague or from subject
matter expert or an admin you would
actually go and Click Share to teams to
quickly explain where you encounter the
errors and what the error was together
with these details what this what this
does it actually helps reduce the amount
of uh the time that uh a person who is
supporting you be your admin or your
partner needs to spend in analyzing
where that error occurs
and what was the context of uh of that
error where it
occurred there are a few other things
few minor things that I think is uh good
to mention and good to know in the help
and support page uh in many of these uh
support
scenarios uh What uh support person is
usually going to ask the user is to
provide like the three basic details in
order to identify the tenant in order to
identify the environment and the company
uh that uh the issue has occurred so
with this release in the help and
support page you have a very easy way of
copying that information and sharing
that information with with with the
support teams we've also uh couple of
months back uh we have also
updated uh our keyboard shortcuts PDFs I
know these are very popular with users
some of them actually have them
laminated uh to to get a quick overview
of uh of the shortcuts especially those
productive users that want to do
everything with a uh with a keyboard and
one last thing that I wanted to mention
in here is that is that there was also
one feature uh that was planned for the
April release which got a bit postponed
and that is uh the the multiple um file
uploads that is actually coming in one
of the upcoming uh minor
releases and with that uh let's switch
to demo and see all of these things in
action for the demo on action bar will
start in my
company this is to show you modern
action bar callout that some users will
receive when they upgrade to 20124
release Wave 1 the call out is informing
existing users of changes in action bar
the call out will be shown just once
only if existing users have teaching
tips enabled only an existing production
environment perment and existing
production
companies this way existing users can
review changes introduced by modern
action bar as for all new users modern
action bar is turned on by
default back in demo company let's
explore action bar improvements such as
addition of the new co-pilot icon spared
captions and reduce baste for search and
Analysis mode so the co-pilot action
search expands when you click on the
icon
and Analysis mode got the new icon which
you can toggle to turn on analysis mode
or turn off analysis mode admins can of
course switch users back to Legacy
action bar experience using the setting
in user settings
page this can of course then be done on
per user
basis in case the user wants to keep the
things the way are and use Legacy action
bar experience in my settings
page the user can turn on Legacy action
bar experience for
himself clicking on work date reveals
the date picker control that is now
aligned with other Microsoft products
and allows for easy exploration of dates
dat are further in the future or
past
this comes in very handy in finance
scenarios 2024 release Wave 1 introduces
automatically generated navigate action
in platform generated error messages for
example adding an item with a missing
product posting group to the sales order
line will generate such
errors users now now can click show item
card to navigate to a place where the
error can be
fixed this is of course true if the user
has permissions to do that in case user
does not have the permission user can
now get unblocked by sharing details
over
teams for example to ask a colleague or
a subject matter expert in his company
about the error
sharing error details is not only
available in inline error messages but
also in the
dialogues when you encounter an issue
where admin or partner help is needed
the user can get a blocked by sharing
details over email as
well when sharing error details via
teams or via email error details are
conveniently copied to cboard and
available for users to pass them in
draft email or teams
message and one other thing help and
support page now has the capability to
easily copy tenants environment session
and user
details this is useful we're asking for
help externally and help Partners
managing multiple customers easily
identify who is reporting the problem
where exactly the problem occur and what
the problem was and find the issue
quickly in
Telemetry in this demo what you saw was
a u modern action bar uh experience um
in action with all the new improvements
you saw the new date picker control uh
you saw how actionable platform
generated errors help users uh get to a
place where they can solve the error you
saw how easy it is to share uh error
details through teams and uh through
Outlook together with all the
environment uh
information and that actually concludes
uh our session uh today if you have the
time I uh urge you to uh have a look at
the these two sessions especially the
the one uh about the mobile app and
barcode scanning because they are going
to they will take a deep dive into
improvements that were made in business
Central mobile app and the other one is
uh more related to a uh General design
guidelines uh for the AI
experiences if you look if you want to
learn more if you want to engage in the
conversation talk to the product team
and so on uh have a look at one of these
resources and reach out to us and with
that uh I want to thank you for your
time and your attention mention in the
session